Eamon Grennan papers, 1964-2010
Emory University
- Writings by Grennan, 1962-2010, Series 2; Boxes 3 - 53; BV 1 - 3
  - Poetry, 1962-2010, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 3 - 39
    - Uncollected poetry, circa 1960s-2010, Subseries 2.1b; Boxes 21 - 31
      - "Divers" (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - "Dog" (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - "Door" (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - "Double Ideogram" (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - "Double Vision" (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - "Dream" (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - "Dream" [Variant title: "Soap and Water"] (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - "Dream Amnesia" (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - "Dream Departures" [Variant title: "Marginal Departures"] (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - "Dream Sequence" (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - "Dreamstuff" (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - "Dresses" [Variant title: "On Dresses"] [Also includes "Lesson in Ethics: The Social Question"] (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - "Driving North, Early Spring" [Variant title: "Driving the Taconic in Early Spring"] (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - "Dusk" [Variant titles: "Room at Dusk," "A Fox at Pompeii," and "Observance"] (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - "Dutch Interior" (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - "Early One December Evening" (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - "Easter Morning Run" (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - "Easter Piece" [Variant title: "Easter Pieces"] (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - "Easter Sunday, Ten A.M." (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - "Eclipse" (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - "Edge" (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - "Edge" [Variant title: Edge Talk"] (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - "Edward Hopper: Sun in an Empty Room (1962)" (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - "The Egrets on Sunset Lake Are" (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - "Eheu, Fugaces" [Variant titles: "Horace to Postumus" and "Horce II, xiv"] [Includes correspondence] (Box 23, Folder 38)
      - "Eighth Wedding Anniversary" [Variant title: "For Our Eighth Wedding Anniversary"] (Box 23, Folder 39)
      - "Elementals" (Box 23, Folder 40)
      - "Encounter" (Box 23, Folder 41)
      - "Encounters" (Box 23, Folder 42)
      - "Ends" (Box 23, Folder 43)
      - "Entering into the Era of Storms" (Box 23, Folder 44)
      - "Entrances" (Box 23, Folder 45)
      - "Ephemera" (Box 23, Folder 46)
      - "Erasure" (Box 23, Folder 47)
      - "Escape" (Box 23, Folder 48)
      - "Ethical Dimensions" (Box 23, Folder 49)
      - "Evacuation" (Box 23, Folder 50)
      - "Evening" (Box 23, Folder 51)
      - "Event in Renvyle" (Box 23, Folder 52)
      - "Exile" [Variant titles: "By the Way" and "How It Goes On"] (Box 23, Folder 53)
      - "Exile's Winter Walk" (Box 23, Folder 54)
      - "Expecting a Letter" (Box 23, Folder 55)
      - "Eye of the Beholder" (Box 23, Folder 56)
      - "Eye Talk" (Box 23, Folder 57)
      - "The Eyes Have It" (Box 23, Folder 58)
      - "Fact" (Box 23, Folder 59)
      - "Facts of Light" (Box 23, Folder 60)
      - "Fair Exchange" (Box 23, Folder 61)
      - "Falling Asleep" (Box 23, Folder 62)
      - "Family Group" (Box 23, Folder 63)
      - "Family Tree" (Box 23, Folder 64)
      - "Father's Hood" (Box 23, Folder 65)
      - "Fearful Symmetry" (Box 23, Folder 66)
      - "February Haiku" [Also includes "Couple," "Frosty Morning," and "Cows on a Windy Day"] (Box 23, Folder 67)
      - "February Metamorph" (Box 23, Folder 68)
      - "Feeding at Omey" (Box 23, Folder 69)
      - "A Few Last Lines of Laundry" [Variant title: "A Few More Lines of Laundry"] (Box 23, Folder 70)
      - "Field" (Box 23, Folder 71)
      - "The Field" [Variant title: "Field"] (Box 23, Folder 72)
      - "Fieldmouse" (Box 23, Folder 73)
      - "Fight" (Box 23, Folder 74)
      - "Figures" (Box 23, Folder 75)
      - "Fine Line" (Box 23, Folder 76)
      - "Fine Spell" (Box 23, Folder 77)
      - "Fire Drill" (Box 23, Folder 78)
      - "Fireworks" (Box 23, Folder 79)
      - "The First Cuckoo" (Box 23, Folder 80)
      - "First Light, Man on Bridge" (Box 23, Folder 81)
      - "First of May" (Box 23, Folder 82)
      - "First Snow" [Variant title: "Not Making It"] (Box 23, Folder 83)
      - "First Words at Annaghmakerrig" (Box 23, Folder 84)
      - "Fish" (Box 23, Folder 85)
      - "Fish Flesh Fowl" (Box 23, Folder 86)
      - "Fish for Breakfast" (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - "Flies" (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - "Flowers in Bedroom" (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - "Flowering Branch" (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - "Flowers in Venice" (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - "Food for Thought" (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - "For Conor in Dublin" (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - "For Dillon and Gwen in Winston-Salem" (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - "For Example" (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - "For Father Hopkins, Gone a Hundred" [Variant titles: "A Burst for Hopkins," "A Rouse for Hopkins," and "A Rouse for Father Hopkins"] (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - "For Hugo" (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - "For Kira at Eight" [Variant title: "All Saints and Kira Maeve"] (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - "For the Birds" (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - "For the Start of Spring" (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - "Fossil" (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - "Fox" (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - "Fragments in April" (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - "From a Book of Illustrations" (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - "From An Arsonist's Diary" (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - "From the Garden" (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - "From Your Window" (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - "Frosty Morning" [See Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "February Haiku"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Fugitive Light" [Variant titles: "Fugitive," "Fugitives," and "Fugue"] (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - "Fullness in Renvyle" (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - "Gale" (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - "Game" (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - "Garden" (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - "Garden" (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - "Garden Glimpses" (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - "Genesis Observed" (Box 24, Folder 29)
      - "Geology, Meteorology" (Box 24, Folder 30)
      - "Getting On" (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - "Getting the Picture" (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - "Giacometti's Dream" (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - "Gift" (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - "Gift" (Box 24, Folder 35)
      - "Gifts" (Box 24, Folder 36)
      - "Gifts in January" [see Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Midwinter"]
      - "The Given" (Box 24, Folder 37)
      - "Glass" (Box 24, Folder 38)
      - "A Glass of Water" (Box 24, Folder 39)
      - "Glasshouse" [Variant title: "Glasshouse and Prayer"] (Box 24, Folder 40)
      - "Glimmers of a City" [Variant title: "But And"] [Also includes "Design"] (Box 24, Folder 41)
      - "Going Down in History" (Box 24, Folder 42)
      - "Going Home" [Variant title: "Homelands"] (Box 24, Folder 43)
      - "Goldfinch" (Box 24, Folder 44)
      - "Goodbye to Birds" (Box 24, Folder 45)
      - "Grace Before Speech" (Box 24, Folder 46)
      - "Granny" (Box 24, Folder 47)
      - "Grey Afternoon, Early February" (Box 24, Folder 48)
      - "Gulls" (Box 24, Folder 49)
      - "Gulls" (Box 24, Folder 50)
      - "Haiku" (Box 24, Folder 51)
      - "Haiku" (Box 24, Folder 52)
      - "Haiku for T." (Box 24, Folder 53)
      - "Hair of the Dog" (Box 24, Folder 54)
      - "Hands" [Variant title: "Hands, History, Solitude"] (Box 24, Folder 55)
      - "Hangover" (Box 24, Folder 56)
      - "Hangover" [Variant titles: "Hangovers," "Morning After," and "Small Change"] (Box 24, Folder 57)
      - "Happenstance" [Variant title: "Happenings"] (Box 24, Folder 58)
      - "Harbour" (Box 24, Folder 59)
      - "He Left" (Box 24, Folder 60)
      - "He Listens to Women's Voices" (Box 24, Folder 61)
      - "He Sees in Early March Two Sparrows" (Box 24, Folder 62)
      - "Heady Weather" (Box 24, Folder 63)
      - "Heart Attack" (Box 24, Folder 64)
      - "Hearty Reminder" (Box 24, Folder 65)
      - "Her Dream" (Box 24, Folder 66)
      - "Here in the Dark" (Box 24, Folder 67)
      - "Hemlock and Light" (Box 24, Folder 68)
      - "His Friend" (Box 24, Folder 69)
      - "Holding On" [Variant title: "Holding Pattern"] (Box 24, Folder 70)
      - "Home" (Box 24, Folder 71)
      - "Home for the Holidays" (Box 24, Folder 72)
      - "Home Thoughts" [Variant title: "Things on the Wind"] (Box 24, Folder 73)
      - "Home Truths" (Box 24, Folder 74)
      - "Hope" (Box 24, Folder 75)
      - "House" (Box 24, Folder 76)
      - "The House" (Box 24, Folder 77)
      - "House and Garden" [Variant title: "Pastoral"] (Box 24, Folder 78)
      - "House and Home" [Variant title: "362 Hooker Avenue"] (Box 24, Folder 79)
      - "House Work" [See Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Survivor"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "How Are You? She Said" (Box 24, Folder 80)
      - "How Day Starts" (Box 24, Folder 81)
      - "How It Is" (Box 24, Folder 82)
      - "How to Make Friends" (Box 24, Folder 83)
      - "How We Ready for Winter" (Box 24, Folder 84)
      - "Howth, January 1991" (Box 24, Folder 85)
      - "Hungers" (Box 24, Folder 86)
      - "I Walk Out and Back at Dawn, New Hampshire" [Variant title: "I Walk Out and Back in New Hampshire" (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Ice Meadow" (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - "Ice Storm in March" (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - "Ideogrammar" (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - "Illusion" (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - "Illustration" (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - "Imprint" (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - "In a Children's Playground, Wembley Park, London" (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - "In City Plum Tree Blossoming" (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - "In Depth" (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - "In Hiding" (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - "In Place" (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - "In the Dark" (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - "In the Margin" (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - "In the Margin" [Variant title: "Marginal"] (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - "In the National Library" (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - "In the Picture" (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - "In This Dream" (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - "In This Instant" (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - "In This Wet Spring" (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - "Incident" (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - "Insect Climbing Window" [Variant title: "Insect Climbing My Window"] (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - "Inside Glimpses" (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - "Inside Out" (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - "Interlude" (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - "Interruption" (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - "Interventions" [Variant titles: "Letting Be," "Changing Nothing," and "What Doesn't Happen"] (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - "Inventory" (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - "Irish Studies" (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - "Irregular Sestina" (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - "Island Advice for Erica at Two Months" (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - "The Island to Phoebe" (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - "It Is Midwinter" (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - "It Isn't Spring" (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - "January: A Break in the Weather" (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - "January Letter" (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - "Joke" (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - "Journal Entry: October 13, 1984" (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - "July" (Box 25, Folder 39)
      - "July 1977" [Variant title: "Blackout, July 1977"] (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - "June 1, 1983" (Box 25, Folder 41)
      - "Juno, Our Sheltie" (Box 25, Folder 42)
      - "Just Another Day" (Box 25, Folder 43)
      - "Kavagonistes" (Box 25, Folder 44)
      - "A Kind of Truth" (Box 25, Folder 45)
      - "Kira" (Box 25, Folder 46)
      - "Kira at Two" (Box 25, Folder 47)
      - "Kira Dancing" (Box 25, Folder 48)
      - "Kira Waking" [Variant title: "At Two"] (Box 25, Folder 49)
      - "Kiss in Time" (Box 25, Folder 50)
      - "Knots" (Box 25, Folder 51)
      - "Knowing" [Variant titles: "Clouds of Unknowing," "Book of Knowledge," and "Beyond"] (Box 25, Folder 52)
      - "Kom Godt Hjem" (Box 25, Folder 53)
      - "Lake, Early Morning" [Variant title: "Lake"] (Box 25, Folder 54)
      - "Landscape: Sinking In" (Box 25, Folder 55)
      - "Landscape with Figure" (Box 25, Folder 56)
      - "Landscape with Figures" [Variant title: "Continuing Investigation"] (Box 25, Folder 57)
      - "Lapwings in January" (Box 25, Folder 58)
      - "Lark" (Box 25, Folder 59)
      - "Lartique's Photo of Woman Throwing a Large Ball" (Box 25, Folder 60)
      - "Last Drop" (Box 25, Folder 61)
      - "Late August" (Box 25, Folder 62)
      - "Later On" (Box 25, Folder 63)
      - "Learning Conditions" (Box 25, Folder 64)
      - "Leash" (Box 25, Folder 65)
      - "Leavetaking" (Box 25, Folder 66)
      - "Leaves Falling" (Box 25, Folder 67)
      - "Leaving Carolina" (Box 25, Folder 68)
      - "Leaving Renvyle" (Box 25, Folder 69)
      - "Leaving the Garden" (Box 25, Folder 70)
      - "Leaving Venice" (Box 25, Folder 71)
      - "Lesson" (Box 25, Folder 72)
      - "Lesson in Ethics: The Social Question" [See Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Dresses"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Lesson: Ontology, Eggshells, Something Else" (Box 25, Folder 73)
      - "Lessons" (Box 25, Folder 74)
      - "Liberal Learning" (Box 25, Folder 75)
      - "'The Liberation of Saint Peter' by Claude Lorrain" (Box 25, Folder 76)
      - "Life Sentences: First Quarter" (Box 25, Folder 77)
      - "Light" (Box 25, Folder 78)
      - "A Light Touch" (Box 25, Folder 79)
      - "Lights Out in Renvyle" (Box 25, Folder 80)
      - "Lightshards" (Box 25, Folder 81)
      - "Limbo" (Box 25, Folder 82)
      - "Little Room Blues" (Box 25, Folder 83)
      - "Living Here" [Variant title: "Le Bon Dieu Est Dans Les Details"] (Box 25, Folder 84)
      - "Long Distance Short Wave" (Box 25, Folder 85)
      - "Looking for the Words" (Box 25, Folder 86)
      - "Looking into the Fire" (Box 25, Folder 87)
      - "Looks, En Route" (Box 25, Folder 88)
      - "Losses" (Box 25, Folder 89)
      - "Lost and Found" (Box 25, Folder 90)
      - "Love Poem" [Variant title: "Deer"] (Box 25, Folder 91)
      - "Love Signs" (Box 25, Folder 92)
      - "Lovers in Play" (Box 25, Folder 93)
      - "Lovers Travelling" (Box 25, Folder 94)
      - "Love's Empire" (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - "Love's Morning" [Also includes "Bush and Ruined Building] (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - "Lying Awake at Four A.M." (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - "Lying in Bed" (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - "MacDowell Sketch" (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - "Man on the Moon" (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - "March" (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - "March 18, 1996" (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - "March the First, Afternoon" (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - "Marginal" (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - "Marked Path" (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - "Maureen" (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - "Me and Birds" (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - "A Meditation on Fire" [Variant title: "Brief Meditation on Fire"] (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - "Meeting" (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - "Meeting" (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - "Memory of Dead Poet" (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - "Memory of Nancy's Cat, Trollop" (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - "Memory of Yeats at Renvyle" (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - "Mid-Day in a Cloudy Field" (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - "Middle Age" (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - "Middle Life" (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - "Midsummer" (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - "Midwinter" [Also includes "Gifts in January"] (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - "Mind Flight" (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - "Mining" (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - "Minor Details" (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - "Missing. Sentence." (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - "Moment" (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - "Monastery, School, Cloud" (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - "Moonglow" (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - "Morning" (Box 26, Folder 32)
      - "Morning" (Box 26, Folder 33)
      - "Morning Mind" (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - "Morning Noon and Night" (Box 26, Folder 35)
      - "Morning Offering" (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - "Morning Offering in Renvyle" [Variant title: "Morning Offering"] (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - "Morning with Pigeons" (Box 26, Folder 38)
      - "Mornings" (Box 26, Folder 39)
      - "More Keys, More Keys" (Box 26, Folder 40)
      - "Moth" (Box 26, Folder 41)
      - "Mothers in March" (Box 26, Folder 42)
      - "Motions" (Box 26, Folder 43)
      - "Moving" (Box 26, Folder 44)
      - "Music" (Box 26, Folder 45)
      - "Musical Interlude" (Box 26, Folder 46)
      - "My Children" (Box 26, Folder 47)
      - "Myth" (Box 26, Folder 48)
      - "Naming Ache" (Box 26, Folder 49)
      - "Native Words" (Box 26, Folder 50)
      - "Nature, Art, Sex, Death, and Company" (Box 26, Folder 51)
      - "Natural Balance" (Box 26, Folder 52)
      - "The Nature of Things" (Box 26, Folder 53)
      - "Naughty Nocturne" (Box 26, Folder 54)
      - "Navigation" (Box 26, Folder 55)
      - "Near Dawn: The Library" (Box 26, Folder 56)
      - "Near March" (Box 26, Folder 57)
      - "Near Renvyle" (Box 26, Folder 58)
      - "Nearly May" (Box 26, Folder 59)
      - "Negative Can-Can or A Critique of Positivism" (Box 26, Folder 60)
      - "Neighbour" (Box 26, Folder 61)
      - "Neighbour" [See also Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "With Youngest Daughter at Parents' Grave"] (Box 26, Folder 62)
      - "Neighbours-in-Waiting" (Box 26, Folder 63)
      - "New Hampshire Pastoral" (Box 26, Folder 64)
      - "New Year's Chincoteague" (Box 26, Folder 65)
      - "News Photo" (Box 26, Folder 66)
      - "Newsphotos: Way of the World" (Box 26, Folder 67)
      - "Night Bodies" (Box 26, Folder 68)
      - "Night Visitor" (Box 26, Folder 69)
      - "Nine" (Box 26, Folder 70)
      - "No Convictions" [Variant title: "Balancing Act"] (Box 26, Folder 71)
      - "Northbound" (Box 26, Folder 72)
      - "Not Standing Still" [See also Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Resident Aliens"] (Box 26, Folder 73)
      - "Note" (Box 26, Folder 74)
      - "Notebook" (Box 26, Folder 75)
      - "Notes" (Box 26, Folder 76)
      - "Noting" (Box 26, Folder 77)
      - "Now" (Box 26, Folder 78)
      - "Of Loss" [Variant title: "In the Event of Loss"] (Box 26, Folder 79)
      - "Old News" (Box 26, Folder 80)
      - "Old Poet in Spring" [Variant title: "Old Poet"] (Box 26, Folder 81)
      - "Old World Roses" (Box 26, Folder 82)
      - "On a Strand in North Dublin" (Box 26, Folder 83)
      - "On an Ancient Funeral Monument" (Box 26, Folder 84)
      - "On an Anniversary" (Box 26, Folder 85)
      - "On Borders" (Box 26, Folder 86)
      - "On Edge" (Box 26, Folder 87)
      - "On Glass" (Box 26, Folder 88)
      - "On the Narrow Road" (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - "On Reading of Another Enormous Property Deal" (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - "On Sober Consideration" (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - "On the Train Home" (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - "On Violence" (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - "On Waking" (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - "One Art" [Variant title: "The Art of Losing Things"] (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - "One Morning" (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - "Only Evening Coming On" (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - "Open Field" (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - "Orchid" (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - "Order and Other" (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - "Otters" (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - "Out There" (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - "Outside His Window" (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - "Painter and Subject" [Also includes "Cows"] (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - "Parents Going" (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - "Part of the Fray" (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - "Part of the Fray" (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - "Pass" (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - "Passages" (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - "Passing the Native Graveyard" (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - "Passing Zone" (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - "Pastorale in Northern New York" (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - "The Path" (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - "The Path" [Variant title: "Path"] (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - "Paths" [Also includes untitled poem] (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - "Patience" (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - "Patient in St. Pat's" [Variant title: "Patient in Pat's"] [See also Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "City Wildflowers"] (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - "Pavese's Verra La Morte" (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - "Peace" (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - "Persona" (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - "Phone Call" (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - "Photo of Conor" (Box 27, Folder 34)
      - "Picnic" (Box 27, Folder 35)
      - "Picture" (Box 27, Folder 36)
      - "Picture of K.G., Growing" (Box 27, Folder 37)
      - "Plant Manual" (Box 27, Folder 38)
      - "Playground" (Box 27, Folder 39)
      - "Pleasure of Recognition" (Box 27, Folder 40)
      - "Poem" (Box 27, Folder 41)
      - "Poem" (Box 27, Folder 42)
      - "Poem for the Epiphany" (Box 27, Folder 43)
      - "Point in Time" (Box 27, Folder 44)
      - "Poise and Pomegranate" (Box 27, Folder 45)
      - "Poor" (Box 27, Folder 46)
      - "Portal" (Box 27, Folder 47)
      - "Portrait" [Variant title: "Picture in Prospect Of"] (Box 27, Folder 48)
      - "Postcard" [Variant title: "Postcard from Ireland"] (Box 27, Folder 49)
      - "Postcard from the Holy Land" (Box 27, Folder 50)
      - "Potatoes" (Box 27, Folder 51)
      - "Poughkeepsie Terminal: All Change" (Box 27, Folder 52)
      - "Prayerhouse" (Box 27, Folder 53)
      - "Preliminary Words at Parting" (Box 27, Folder 54)
      - "Present Participle" (Box 27, Folder 55)
      - "Progress Report" (Box 27, Folder 56)
      - "Protection Racket" (Box 27, Folder 57)
      - "Province of Signs" (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - "Pumpkin" (Box 27, Folder 59)
      - "Quilt" [Variant titles: "Art Gallery," "Quick Takes: First of May," and "Question"] (Box 27, Folder 60)
      - "Raccoon" [Variant title: "She Forgives the Raccoon"] (Box 27, Folder 61)
      - "Radiance of Dust" (Box 27, Folder 62)
      - "Raking" (Box 27, Folder 63)
      - "Rapture Saturday" (Box 27, Folder 64)
      - "Reading" (Box 27, Folder 65)
      - "Reading Reading" (Box 27, Folder 66)
      - "Realism and Romance: Lesson One" (Box 27, Folder 67)
      - "Recognitions" (Box 27, Folder 68)
      - "Recognitions" (Box 27, Folder 69)
      - "Recovery" (Box 27, Folder 70)
      - "Recovery" (Box 27, Folder 71)
      - "Red Squirrel in Maple" (Box 27, Folder 72)
      - "Reflection" (Box 27, Folder 73)
      - "Reflections of a Runner" (Box 27, Folder 74)
      - "Regarding Ryder's House by Edward Hopper" (Box 27, Folder 75)
      - "Reign of Fire" (Box 27, Folder 76)
      - "Remember" (Box 27, Folder 77)
      - "Remembering Venice" (Box 27, Folder 78)
      - "A Reminder" (Box 27, Folder 79)
      - "Reminder" (Box 27, Folder 80)
      - "Reminder" (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - "Renvyle Garden" (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - "Renvyle Stroll" [Variant title: "Renvyle Evening"] (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - "Report from the Front" [Variant titles: "Brief Report from the Front" and "Mind How You Go"] (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - "Reproductions" (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - "Requiem" [Variant titles: "Requiem in Waiting" and "Forage Requiem"] (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - "Resident Aliens" [Also includes "Not Standing Still"] (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - "Resolution" (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - "Return" (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - "Returning to Deadman Cove" (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - "Revelation" (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - "Revelations, Maybe" (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - "Richard Hugo" (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - "Riff" (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - "Riff of Space and Skin" (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - "Rising to It" (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - "Risking the Obvious" (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - "Robin" (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - "Robin in Thornbush" [Also includes "Bird Garden"] (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - "Rocks in Renvyle" [Variant title: "On the Rocks in Renvyle"] (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - "Roman Empire" (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - "Room and Sun" (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - "Roses" (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - "Rough Art" (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - "Running through Easter Sunday Morning" (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - "Sadness of Birds" (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - "Safe Home" (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - "Salt Marsh, Rainy Night" (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - "Sandwriting" (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - "Sarah Thinks of Her Sick Dog and Vice Versa" (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - "Satori" (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - "Saturday Afternoon, Late October" (Box 28, Folder 32)